# # [ Woman Vocalizing ]
# # [ Fades ]
- Are you a doctor ? - Yes . Yes .
He 's an actor .
Oh , an actor . We 're very popular with actors .
Have I , uh , seen you in anything ?
Well , let 's see . I did Hamlet a while back . Didn 't I , Liz ?
And then we did The Sandpiper , and then ...
He 's joking . He was in Luther and Nobody Loves An Albatross ...
and a lot of television plays and commercials .
That 's where the money is , isn 't it ... commercials ?
And the artistic thrills too .
Seven , Diego .
Originally the smallest apartment was a nine .
They 've been broken up into four , fives , and sixes .
7-E is a four .
Originally the back part of a ten .
It has the original dining room for its living room ...
another bedroom for the bedroom ...
and two servants ' rooms thrown together ...
for a dining room or a second bedroom .
- Do you have children ? - [ Man ] Uh ...
- [ Woman ] Uh , we plan to . - [ Gate Squeaking ]
- # # [ Piano : Scales ] - We must oil that gate , Diego .
This way , please .
The previous tenant , Mrs. Gardenia , passed away ...
just a few days ago , so nothing has been moved yet .
Her son asked me to say that some of the furniture ...
can be picked up practically for the asking .
- Did she die in the apartment ? - [ Buzzer Sounds ]
- Not that it makes any difference . - Oh , no , no , no . In a hospital .
She 'd been in a coma for weeks .
- After you , please . - Thank you .
She was very old and passed away without ever waking .
I 'd be grateful to go that way myself when the time comes .
Oh , no , no , no . Not in the apartment , no .
- # # [ Piano : " Für Elise " ] - She was chipper right to the end .
One of the first women lawyers in New York City .
She did a little gardening on the side too .
She was quite a woman .
Oh , closet . Oh , plenty of closets .
A nice view of the park . Oh , very nice view .
Now , this room , for instance ... it would make a lovely nursery .
Yes , yellow-and-white wallpaper would brighten it tremendously .
What are all these things here ?
- Herbs , mostly . - A nice , large bathroom ...
Mint , basil ...
- No marijuana ? - [ Man Clears Throat ]
Come on .
The , uh , master bedroom .
Oh , yes .
Here we are , back at the hallway again .
- [ Woman ] Oh , yes . - There .
Oh ! Oh , Guy !
- Yeah . - [ Gasps ]
- Fireplace works , of course . - That 's right .
Oh !
Oh , it 's a wonderful apartment ! I love it !
See what she 's trying to do ? She 's trying to get you to lower the rent .
Yes , well , we 'd raise it if we were allowed .
Apartments with this kind of charm ...
Why , that 's odd !
There 's a closet behind that secretary .
I 'm su ... I 'm sure there is .
Yeah ... Oh , I think you 're right .
She moved it . It used to be there .
Give me a hand , will you ?
[ Grunting , Laughing ]
I see now why she went into a coma !
She couldn 't have lifted it by herself . She was 89 .
Should we open it ? Maybe her son should .
I 'm authorized to show the apartment .
Well !
Whoever she locked in got out .
Or perhaps she didn 't need five closets .
But why would she cover up her vacuum cleaner and her towels ?
Hmm . I don 't suppose we 'll ever know .
Maybe she was becoming senile after all . Is there anything else ?
Yes , please . What about the laundry facilities ?
It 's bigger than the other one .
Yeah . It 's more expensive too , you know ?
It 's better located .
Yeah , well , God knows I could walk to all the theaters from here .
Oh , Guy , let 's take it . Please ?
That living room could be ... Oh , please let 's take it .
Okay , darlin ' . We get out of the other lease , okay .
[ Man ] I was tempted to write the management that you were ...
drug addicts and litterbugs .
Instead , I decided to lie and tell them you were wonderful tenants .
- Ah , you 're great , Hutch . - Wish I could talk you out of it , though .
- He 's pulling your leg , Ro , honey . - Indeed I 'm not .
Now , that looks great . That is ...
Are you aware that the Bramford had rather an unpleasant reputation ...
around the turn of the century ?
It 's where the Trench sisters conducted ...
their little dietary experiments ...
and Keith Kennedy held his parties .
Adrian Marcato lived there too . So did Pearl Ames .
- Who were the Trench sisters ? - Who was Adrian Marcato ?
The Trench sisters were two proper Victorian ladies .
They cooked and ate several young children , including a niece .
- Oh , lovely . - Adrian Marcato practiced witchcraft .
He made quite a splash in the ' 90s by announcing ...
that he 'd conjured up the living devil .
Apparently people believed him , so they attacked ...
and nearly killed him in the lobby of the Bramford .
- You 're joking . - Later the Keith Kennedy business began ...
and by the ' 20s , the house was half empty .
I knew about Keith Kennedy . I didn 't know that Marcato lived there .
- [ Ro ] And those sisters . - World War II filled the house up again .
- [ Ro ] Terrific . - [ Guy ] What , the house ?
- The lamb . - They called it " Black Bramford . "
But Hutch , awful things happen in every apartment house .
But this house has a high incidence of unpleasant happenings .
In ' 59 , a dead infant was found ...
wrapped in newspaper in the basement .
Mmm . You really rouse my appetite .
Have some more wine .
[ Woman ] Roman ?
Bring me in some root beer when you come .
[ Guy Chuckling ]
Hey , these are shelves .
Hey , let 's make love .
- [ Creaking ] - Shh !
I think I hear the Trench sisters chewing .
Oh !
[ Ro ] Straight up to the left .
[ Man On TV ] Here at Daytona , Florida , it 's the 250 cc 100-Mile Classic ...
with Yamaha leading the pack on the final lap and winning it ...
as Yamaha takes seven of the top ten places .
It 's the third straight year for Yamaha ... a clean sweep .
[ Man On TV ] Yamaha is race-bred from champions .
And as you can see , we have a model for every kind of riding .
[ Chuckles ] You know , you really should discover the swingin ' world of Yamaha .
Why don 't you get on , have a ride ? Go on .
Okay . Come on . Let 's go .
Look .
It 's great .
[ Chuckles ] I 'm sorry .
I thought you were Victoria Vetri , the actress .
I 'm sorry .
It 's all right . A lot of people think I 'm Victoria .
- I don 't see any resemblance . - Do you know her ?
No .
My name is Terry Gionoffrio .
Nice to meet you . I 'm Rosemary Woodhouse .
Uh , we 're new tenants here .
I 'm staying with the Castevets , the seventh floor .
I 'm their guest , sort of , since June .
Our apartment used to be the back part of yours .
Oh , for goodness ' sakes . You took the old lady 's apartment , Mrs ...
Yeah , um , Miss ... Gar-Gardenia .
Gardenia . Yeah . She was a good friend of the Castevets .
She used to grow herbs and things for her to cook with .
- I saw those plants . - Well , now she grows her own things .
- [ Buzzer Sounds ] - Excuse me a moment . I have to put the softener in .
- What does your husband do ? - He 's an actor .
- No kidding ? What 's his name ? - Guy Woodhouse .
He was in Luther and Nobody Loves An Albatross ...
and he does a lot of television and radio .
Gee , I watch TV all day long . I 'll bet I 've seen him .
[ Glass Shatters ]
- Wow ! - Ooh !
- I hate this basement . - Yeah , me too .
Gives me the creeps .
Listen , why don 't we come down here together regular and do our laundry ?
Okay , that 'd be great .
I have a good-luck charm . It might work for both of us .
- Oh , that 's beautiful . - Yeah , isn 't it ?
- Mm-hmm ! - Mrs. Castevet gave it to me . It 's good luck .
Or anyway , it 's supposed to be . It 's got some stuff inside .
I 'm not mad about the smell either . I hope it works .
It 's a beautiful charm , though . I 've never seen anything like it .
European .
The Castevets are the most wonderful people in the world , bar none .
They picked me up off the sidewalk , literally .
You were sick ?
I was starving and on dope and doing a lot of other things .
They 're childless , though . I 'm like the daughter they never had .
At first I thought they wanted me for some kind of a sex thing ...
but they 've turned out to be like real grandparents .
It 's nice to know there are people like that ...
when you hear so much about apathy ...
and people who are afraid of getting involved .
I 'd be dead now if it wasn 't for them .
That 's an absolute fact . Dead or in jail .
You don 't have any family that could 've helped you ?
[ Scoffs ] A brother in the navy .
[ Woman ] Why , it 's impossible to be a hundred percent sure .
If you want my opinion , we shouldn 't tell her at all .
- That 's my opinion ! - That must be the partition .
It 's the back part of the original ten with a dining room .
And there 's ... there 's a closet over here ...
and then there 's a closet over here .
[ Ritualistic Chanting ]
# # [ Recorder ]
[ Chanting Continues ]
# # [ Recorder Continues ]
- [ People Clamoring ] - [ Horns Honking ]
- [ Woman ] What floor ? - [ Man ] Seven .
[ Man ] Stay back , will ya , lady ?
[ Woman Talking Over Police Radio , Indistinct ]
Get back , now , will you , please ? Get back . There 's nothin ' to see .
- [ Guy ] Oh , my God ! - Get back , will you , please ?
Jesus !
- Get back ! - We know her .
- What 's her name ? - Terry .
Terry what ?
Ro ?
What was her name again ? Terry what ?
Uh , I don 't remember . An Italian name .
She was staying with some people named Castevet . 7-A .
Yeah , we got that already .
Short and sweet . She stuck it to the windowsill with a Band-Aid .
- Theresa Gionoffrio . - [ Policeman ] Move on !
Move on !
- You knew her ? - Only slightly .
- Come on , Ro . Let 's go . - Oh ! Here they come .
You folks the Castevets on the seventh floor ?
We are .
You have a young woman named Theresa Gionoffrio living with you ?
We do . What 's wrong ? Has there been an accident ?
You 'd better brace yourself for some bad news .
She 's dead . Jumped out of the window .
That 's not possible . That 's a mistake .
Artie , want to let these folks take a look , please ?
I knew this would happen .
She got deeply depressed every three weeks or so .
I told my wife about it , but she pooh-poohed me .
Well , I ... It doesn 't mean she killed herself .
She was a very happy girl with no reason for self-destruction .
She ... must 've been cleanin the windows or something .
- She wasn 't cleaning windows at midnight . - Why not ? Maybe she was .
Is that her handwriting ?
- Yeah . - Definitely . Absolutely .
Thank you . I 'll see this gets back to you when we 're done with it .
I don 't believe it . I just don 't believe it .
- She was so happy . - Who 's the next of kin ?
Ah , she was all alone . She didn 't have anybody . Only us .
- [ Rosemary ] Didn 't she have a brother ? - Did she ?
She said she did ... in the navy .
[ Mrs. Castevet ] It 's news to me .
[ Policeman ] Do you know where he 's stationed ?
No , I don 't .
She mentioned him to me in the laundry room .
- I 'm Rosemary Woodhouse . - Uh , we 're in 7-E .
I feel just the way you do , Mrs. Castevet .
She seemed so happy and full of ...
She said wonderful things about you and your husband , how grateful she was .
Thank you .
Know anything else about this brother except he 's in the navy ?
- No , I don 't . - It should be easy to find him .
- I 'm so stunned and so sorry . - Yeah , it 's such a pity .
Well , thank you .
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Mrs. Castevet 's Voice ] Sometimes I wonder how come you 're the leader of anything !
Please don 't tell me what Laura-Louise said ...
because I 'm not interested !
If you 'd listened to me , we wouldn 't have had to do this !
We 'd have been all set to go now instead of havin ' to start all over from scratch !
Shh !
I told you not to tell her in advance !
I told you she wouldn 't be open-minded !
I told Sister Veronica about the windows ...
and she withdrew the school from the competition . Otherwise ...
[ Door Buzzer Sounds ]
Hello . How are you ?
- Fine . May I come in a minute ? - Yes , of course . Please do .
I just come over to thank you for saying those nice things the other night .
- Oh , no , please ... - Poor Terry .
We thought maybe we failed her some way ...
though her note made it crystal clear we hadn 't .
You 'll never know how helpful it was in such a shock moment .
So I do thank you . Roman does too . Roman 's my hubby .
You 're welcome . I 'm glad I could help .
Yeah . Well , she was cremated yesterday .
Now we gotta forget and go on .
It won 't be easy . We don 't have children of our own . You have any ?
- No , we don 't . - No ? Well , there you ...
Oh ! That 's a nice ...
Look how you put the table ! Isn 't that interesting ?
- I saw it in a magazine . - Oh , my .
Nice paint job . Oh .
Oh . Oh , that 's nice . What is that ? That 's the TV room ?
Well , only temporarily . It 's going to be a nursery .
- Oh , you pregnant ? - No , not yet .
- I hope to be as soon as we 're settled . - Wonderful .
Well , you 're young and healthy . You ought to have lots of children .
We plan to have three .
Dying to see what you did to this apartment .
The woman who had it before was a dear friend of mine .
- I know . Terry told me . - Oh , did she ?
- You two had some long talks together in the laundry room , huh ? - Only one .
[ Exclaims ] Oh , my goodness !
Ah , it looks so much brighter .
What do you pay for a chair like that ?
Uh ... Oh , I 'm not sure , really .
I think about $ 200 .
What does your hubby do ?
- # # [ Piano : " Für Elise " ] - He 's an actor .
I knew it ! I said it to Roman yesterday .
He 's so good-lookin ' . What movies was he in ?
No movies . He was in two plays ...
called Luther and Nobody Loves An Albatross ...
and a lot of television and radio .
Listen , Rosemary , I got a two-inch-thick sirloin steak ...
sittin ' defrostin ' this minute .
Why don 't you and Guy come over and have supper with us tonight ? What do you say ?
- Oh , no , we couldn 't . - Why not ?
- No . Really , that 's very kind of you , but ... - It would be a real help to us .
[ Sighs ] First night we 'll be alone since ...
Are you sure it wouldn 't be too much trouble for you ?
Honey , if it was trouble , I wouldn 't ask you .
All right . You go ahead and count on us . I 'll have to check with Guy , though .
Listen , you tell him I won 't take no for an answer .
Oh , here 's your mail . Nah , ads .
Thank you .
[ Door Shuts ]
Yoo-hoo !
Donald Baumgart got that part .
It 's a bad play anyway .
Even if it folds out of town , it 's the kind of part that gets noticed .
Mrs. Castevet was here ...
to thank me for what I said about Terry .
She is the nosiest person I 've ever seen .
You know she actually asked the prices of things ?
- No kidding . - Mm .
She invited us to have dinner with them tonight .
I told her I 'd have to check with you but that it 'd probably be okay .
Oh , Jesus . We don 't have to do that , do we , honey ?
I think they 're lonely .
We get friendly with an old couple like that , we 'll never get rid of them .
They 're right across the wall .
I told her she could count on us .
- You don 't have to sulk about it . - I 'm not sulking .
I see exactly what you mean .
- Hell , we 'll go . - No , no . What for ?
- We 'll go ! - No , we don 't have to if you don 't want to .
That sounds so phony , but I really mean it .
Really , I do .
Be my good deed for today .
Okay , but only if you want to .
And we 'll make it clear it 's just for this one night ...
and not the beginning of anything , right ?
Ah , perfect timing ! Come on in .
Roman 's fixing some vodka blushes .
My , I 'm glad you could come , Guy .
I 'm fixin ' to tell everybody that I knew you when .
Look , dinner isn 't ready just yet , but sit down there anywhere , love .
Take a seat on the couch . You 're gonna find yourself very ...
I seem to have overfilled the glasses .
No , no , no . Don 't get up .
Generally I pour these out precisely as a bartender . Don 't I , Minnie ?
- Just watch the carpet . - But this evening I made a little too much ...
Ah , there we are . No , no , no . Sit down , please .
- Now , Mrs. Woodhouse . - Thank you .
Mr. Woodhouse , uh , vodka blush ?
- Yes , thanks . - Have you ever tasted one ?
- No , no , I haven 't . - It looks delicious .
Minnie . They 're very popular in Australia .
Now , to our guests . Welcome to our home .
- Hear , hear . - Cheers .
- [ Liquid Splattering ] - [ Coughing ]
The carpet !
- [ Roman ] Oh , dear . - Brand-new carpet .
This man 's so clumsy !
- Do you come from Australia ? - Oh , no , no .
I 'm from right here in New York City . I 've been there , though .
I 've been everywhere , literally .
You name a place , and I 've been there .
- Go ahead . Name a place . - [ Guy ] Fairbanks , Alaska .
I 've been there . Been all over Alaska .
Yes , Fairbanks , Juneau , Anchorage ...
Nome , Sitka , Seward .
- I spent four months there in ' 38 . - Where are you folks from ?
- Well ... - Well , I ...
I 'm from Omaha . Guy 's from Baltimore .
Omaha 's a good city . Baltimore is too .
- Do you travel for business ? - Well , business and pleasure both .
I 'm 79 , and I 've been going one place or another since I was ten .
- You name a place , I 've been there . - [ Bell Dings ]
Ah ! Steak 's ready . Don 't rush your drinks , now .
Roman , take your pill .
[ Roman ] No pope ever visits a city where the newspapers are on strike .
I heard he 's gonna postpone and wait till it 's over .
- [ Guy ] Well , that 's showbiz . - [ Guy , Adrian , Minnie Laughing ]
That 's exactly what it is .
All the costumes , the rituals ... all religions .
Oh , oh , I think we 're offending ' Rosemary .
- No. no . - You 're not religious , my dear , are you ?
Well , I-I was brought up a Catholic . Now I don 't know .
- Yeah . You looked uncomfortable . - Well , he is the pope .
Well , now , you don 't need to have respect for him ...
because he pretends that he 's holy .
[ Guy ] Now , that 's a good point .
When I think what they spend on robes and jewels !
A good picture of the hypocrisy behind organized religion ...
was given , I thought , in Luther .
Did you ever get to play that leading part , Guy ?
Me ? No .
Well , weren 't you Albert Finney 's understudy ?
- No . - Well , that 's strange .
I remember being struck by a gesture you made ...
and checking in the program to see who you were .
- Thank you . - Um , what gesture was that ?
Well , I 'm not sure now . It was a reaction , uh ...
I did a thing with my arms when Luther was having a fit .
- It was a kind of involuntary reaching . - That 's it . That 's it .
- It had a wonderful authenticity to it . - [ Guy Chuckles ] Come on , now .
No , no . I mean it .
My father was a theatrical producer ...
and my early years were spent in the company ...
of Mrs. Fiske , Forbes-Robertson , Modjeska .
- Guy ? - Oh , yes , please .
You have a most interesting inner quality , Guy .
It appears in your television work too . It should take you a long way indeed ...
provided , of course , that you get those initial breaks .
Are you preparing for a show now ?
Um , well , I 'm up for a couple parts .
- Well , I can 't believe that you won 't get them . - Well , I can .
I 'd like to have a spice garden someday .
I guess I 'm a country girl at heart .
- You come from a big family ? - Mm-hmm . Three brothers and two sisters .
- Your sisters married ? - Mm-hmm .
- They have children ? - One has two . The other has four .
Well , there 's a chance you 'll have lots of children too .
Oh , we 're fertile , all right .
I 've got 16 nieces and nephews .
My goodness !
Would you like me to wash , and you can wipe for a while ?
Oh , no . This is fine , dear .
Now , Roman , will you stop bending Guy 's ears with your Modjeska stories ?
He 's only listening 'cause he 's polite .
No , no , no , no . It 's very interesting , Mrs. Castevet .
- You see ? - Minnie . I 'm Minnie , he 's Roman . Okay ?
- Okay ? - [ Rosemary ] Okay .
Okay . Terrific . Just terrific .
- Good-bye , darlin ' . Good-bye . - Thank you for having us .
- Yeah , it was lovely . Bless you . - Minnie !
Minnie ! Ya great kid , ya !
Whoo ! About that steak , huh ?
Oh , my God ! And the cake ! How did you eat two pieces ?
- It was weird ! - Out of politeness .
That 's how I ate two pieces ... out of politeness .
[ Rosemary Laughing ]
- Only three dinner plates that match ... - Shh !
And all that beautiful , beautiful silver .
- We 'll be nice . Maybe they 'll will it to us . - Oh !
Yeah .
- Guess what they have in their bathroom . - A bidet .
- Jokes for the John . - No .
A book on a hook , right next to the toilet .
Roman 's stories are pretty damned interesting , though .
Never even heard of Forbes-Robertson before .
I 'm gonna go over there again tomorrow night and hear some more .
- You are ? - Yeah . He asked me .
Here , do this damn thing for me , will you ?
I thought we were gonna do something with Joan and Dick Jellico .
- Was that definite ? - Well , it wasn 't definite .
We 'll see them next week .
You don 't have to come along if you don 't want to , you know .
You can stay here .
I think I will stay here .
He knew Henry Irving too . I mean , really interesting , huh ?
Why did they take their pictures down ?
- What do you mean ? - Their pictures ... they took them down .
There are hooks in the wall and clean spaces ...
and the one picture that is there doesn 't fit .
I didn 't notice that .
# # [ Slow Jazz ]
[ Door Buzzer Sounds ]
Hi , dear . We 're not botherin ' ya , are we ?
This is my dear friend Laura-Louise McBurney . Lives up on 12 .
Laura-Louise , this is Guy 's wife , Rosemary .
Hello , Rosemary . Welcome to the Bram .
Laura-Louise just met Guy . She wanted to meet you too .
- Could we come in ? - Uh , of ... of course . Please do .
Well , there you are . Go ahead .
Look at the ... [ Indistinct ]
Oh ! Gosh !
Isn 't that beautiful ?
- It came this morning . - Are you all right , dear ? You look worn .
Oh , no . I 'm fine . It 's the first day of my period .
And you 're up and around ? On my first day ...
I experienced such pain , I couldn 't move , eat , or anything .
Dan used to give me gin through a straw to kill the pain .
Girls today take things much more in their stride .
- They 're much healthier than we were ... - # # [ Off ]
thanks to vitamins , better medical care ...
What are those things over there ? Seat covers ?
Um , cushions for the window seats .
Oh , yeah .
[ Gasps ] Oh , before I forget ...
this is for you , from Roman and me .
For me ?
It 's just a little present , is all . For moving ' in .
- There 's no reason ... - It 's real old . It 's over 300 years .
It 's lovely .
Yeah . The green inside is called tannis root .
That 's for good luck .
It 's lovely , but I can 't accept it .
- You already have . Put it on . - Yeah .
[ Chuckles ] You 'll get used to the smell before you know it .
Yeah , go on .
[ Minnie ] Ah , yeah .
Were his stories as interesting as last night ?
Yes . Did you have a good time ?
All right . I got a present .
- It was Terry 's . - No kidding .
Kind of pretty , though .
- Aren 't you gonna wear it ? - Mm-mm . It smells .
There 's stuff in it called tannis root from her greenhouse .
[ Chuckles ] Not too bad , though .
- Tannis , anyone ? - Well , if you took it ...
you ought to wear it . [ Chuckles ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
Hello ?
Yes . This is he .
Oh . God , no .
- Oh , the poor guy . - [ Man On Phone , Indistinct ]
And , uh , they don 't have any idea what 's causing it ?
- No , not yet . - My God , that 's awful . That 's just awful .
We 'd like to know if you 'd be interested ... [ Indistinct ]
Yes , I would .
I mean , yes , I am .
[ Chuckles ] I hate to get it that way , but ...
Well , you 'd have to speak to my agent about that end of it .
Allan Stone .
I 'm sure there won 't be any problem , Mr. Weiss , not as far as we 're concerned .
Thank you , Mr. Weiss .
Guy ?
What is it ?
Donald Baumgart ... he 's gone blind .
He woke up yesterday , and he can 't see .
- Oh , no . - Oh , I 've got the part .
Well , it 's a hell of a way to get it .
Listen , uh , I have to get out and walk around .
Yeah , I understand . Go ahead .
Baumgart . Donald Baumgart .
[ Rosemary ] It 's a fascinating part . He 'll really be noticed this time .
He also has an offer for a lead in a television series : Miami Beach .
He 's suddenly very hot .
Mm , now I understand why you 're so overjoyed .
Well , it 's a difficult period in his life .
A challenge .
I see .
You know how actors are . They 're all a bit self-centered .
I 'll bet even Laurence Olivier is vain and self-centered .
It 's a difficult part . He 's got to work with crutches ...
and naturally he 's preoccupied ...
and he ... well , preoccupied . [ Voice Quavering ]
I say , you had another suicide up there at Happy House .
- Oh , didn 't I tell you ? - No , you didn 't .
It was that girl I told you about : the drug addict ...
who was rehabilitated by this old couple , the Castevets .
I 'm sure I told you that .
[ Chuckling ] They didn 't rehabilitate her very successfully , it seems .
[ Door Shuts ]
I 've been a creep .
It 's from worrying if Baumgart would regain his sight , rat that I am .
Well , it 's natural . You 're bound to feel two ways about it .
Even if I 'm Mr. Yamaha for the rest of my days ...
I 'm gonna stop giving you the short end of the stick .
- You haven 't been . - Yes , I have .
I 've been tearing my hair out over my career .
Let 's have a baby , all right ?
Let 's have three babies , one at a time , all right ?
A baby . You know ... " Mama , Dada , poo-poo . " You know ?
- You mean it ? - Sure , I mean it . Sure , I mean it .
I even figured out the right time to start . Look .
You really mean it ? Really ?
No , I 'm kidding . Sure , I mean it .
Oh , Ro , honey , for God sakes , don 't cry , all right ?
- Oh , no . I won 't . - [ Chuckling ]
- # # [ Slow Jazz ] - Here goes nothin ' .
Mm , mm , mm ! The paint ! The paint !
Good grief .
Nobody , but nobody , has a fire tonight .
Isn 't it gorgeous ?
I hope we have the coldest winter ever .
[ Door Buzzer Sounds ]
Aw , shit !
- [ Minnie ] Hi , Guy . How are ya ? - Oh , hello .
No . Don 't let her in . Not tonight .
[ Minnie , Guy Talking , Indistinct ]
Oh , you sure you don 't want to come in ?
[ Minnie ] No . [ Indistinct ]
[ Door Shuts , Lock Clicks ]
Good .
Who says there 's nothing to ESP ?
[ French Accent ] Madame et Monsieur shall have ze dessert after all !
Mousse au chocolat ... or as Minnie calls it ...
" chocolate mouse . "
I was afraid she 'd stay all evening .
Oh , she just wanted us to try it .
[ Imitating Minnie ] Seein ' it 's one of her speci-al-ities .
It was sweet of her , really . We shouldn 't make fun of her .
Yeah you 're right . You 're right . Mm-hmm .
Mmm . It 's good .
# # [ Ends ]
Has an under-taste .
A chalky under-taste .
I don 't get it .
That 's silly , honey . There is no under-taste .
There is .
Come on . The old bat slaved all day . Now eat it .
- I don 't like it . - It 's delicious .
Here . You can have mine .
All right . Don 't eat it . There 's always something wrong .
Oh , if it 's gonna turn into a big thing ...
If you really can 't stand it , just don 't eat it .
Mmm . It 's delicious .
No under-taste at all .
Would you turn the record over , please ?
[ Silverware Clatters ]
# # [ Resumes ]
There , Daddy . Do I get a gold star ?
You get two of them .
- I 'm sorry if I was stuffy . - You were .
[ Man On TV ] ... is making a full circle of the park ...
It 's the pope at Yankee Stadium !
- walking to his specially built canopy at second base . - Christ , what a mob !
[ Man On TV ] Listen to that crowd roar .
Everywhere the pope has been today he has received this type of reception .
As one nun put it this afternoon ...
" Perhaps we are being undignified , but this is a special day . "
And a special day it has been .
That 's a great spot for my Yamaha commercial .
We 'd like to give you a brief summary of today 's historic happenings .
- Pope Paul VI arrived at 9 : 27 a.m. this morning ... - [ TV Fades ]
[ Guy ] What is it ?
Dizzy .
- Hey . - [ Forced Chuckle ]
No wonder .
You had all that booze in you .
Probably didn 't eat anything all day before dinner , huh ?
Hey .
[ Rosemary ] Nice .
Sleep is what you need . A good night 's sleep .
We have to make a baby .
Oh , well ...
we 'll-we 'll do it .
Tomorrow . There 's plenty of time , hmm ?
Just a nap .
[ Clock Ticking ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Why are you taking them off ?
To make you more comfortable .
I am more comfortable .
Sleep , Ro .
[ Wind Gusting ]
[ Ticking Continues ]
[ Rosemary ] Isn 't Hutch coming with us ?
Catholics only .
I wish we weren 't bound by these prejudices ...
but unfortunately ...
[ Guy ] Easy , easy . You 've got her too high .
Typhoon ! Typhoon !
It killed 55 people in London ...
You 'd better go down below , miss .
[ Chanting In Foreign Language ]
- She 's awake . She sees . - She don 't see .
As long as she ate the " mouse , " she can 't see nor hear . She 's like dead . Now sing .
[ Chanting ]
[ Chanting Fades ]
[ Woman ] I 'm sorry to hear you aren 't feeling well .
It 's only the mouse bite .
You 'd better have your legs tied down ...
in case of convulsions .
Yes , I suppose so .
There 's always a chance it was rabid .
If the music bothers you , let me know ...
and I 'll have it stopped .
Oh , no , no , no , no .
Please don 't change the program on my account .
[ Woman ] Try to sleep .
We 'll be waiting up on deck .
This is no dream ! This is really happening !
They tell me you have been bitten by a mouse .
Yes . That 's why I couldn 't come to see you .
Oh , that 's all right .
We wouldn 't want you to jeopardize your health .
Am I forgiven , Father ?
Oh , absolutely .
Hey , it 's after 9 : 00 .
[ Moans ] Five minutes .
I have to be at Allan 's at 10 : 00 .
- Eat out . - The hell I will !
What time is it ?
It 's , uh , ten after 9 : 00 .
What time did I go to sleep ?
You didn 't go to sleep . You passed out .
Uh , from now on you get ...
cocktails or wine , not cocktails and wine , huh ?
The dreams I had !
Don 't yell . I already filed ' em down .
I didn 't want to miss baby night .
- You ... While I was out ? - And a couple of my nails were ragged ...
and it was kind of fun in a necrophile sort of way .
- [ Brushing Teeth ] - I dreamed someone was raping me .
I don 't know . Someone inhuman .
Thanks a lot !
- What 's the matter ? - Nothing .
I didn 't want to miss the night .
We could 've done it this morning or tonight .
Last night wasn 't the only split second .
Well , I was a little bit loaded myself , you know .
[ Horns Honking ]
- Oh , hello there . Did you like it ? - Oh , yes .
I think I put a little too much crème de cacao in it .
No , no . It was delicious . You 'll have to give me the recipe .
Yeah , I 'd love to . Listen , you goin ' shoppin ' ?
Do me a little teeny favor , will ya ? Get me six eggs , a small Instant Sanka .
- I 'm gonna pay you later , huh ? - All right . Bye-bye .
Don 't you think we ought to talk about it ?
About what ?
The way you haven 't been looking at me .
What are you talking about ? I 've been looking at you .
- You haven 't . - Why , sure I have .
Now , what is it ? What 's the matter ?
Nothing . Never mind .
No , no . Don 't say that . What is it ?
Nothing .
Look , honey , I know I 've been preoccupied ...
with the part and all , but it is important .
That doesn 't mean I don 't love you .
# # [ Piano : " Für Elise " ]
It was due on Friday .
- It was ? - Mm-hmm .
- It 'll probably come tonight or tomorrow . - Wanna bet ?
- Yeah . - A quarter .
- Okay . - You 're gonna lose .
Shut up , will ya ? You 're getting me all jumpy .
It 's only been two days .
When will I know ?
I 'll call you just as soon as I get the results .
I like to do a general examination just to know something more .
It was Elise Dunstan who recommended you to me , Doctor .
- Oh , yes . How is she ? - She 's fine .
And the boys are great . Did you deliver all of them ?
No , just the last . Universal hemoglobin .
Yes , Doctor .
[ Water Running ]
- We went to see The Fantasticks . - Oh , did you ?
- Mm . - Did you enjoy it ?
- Yeah . - Good .
[ Ringing ]
- Hello ? - [ Doctor ] Mrs. Woodhouse ?
- Dr. Hill ? - Congratulations .
- Really ? - Really .
Are you there ?
Uh , yes . Um , what happens now ?
Very little . You come see me next month ...
and you get those Natalin pills ... one a day .
- I 'll mail you forms for the hospital . - Uh , when will it be ?
Uh , it works out to be June 28 .
- That sounds so far away . - It is .
- Yeah . - Oh , one more thing , Mrs. Woodhouse .
- We 'd like another blood sample . - Oh , yes , of course .
- What for ? - Uh , the nurse didn 't take enough .
- So would you drop by and see her ? - But I-I am pregnant , aren 't I ?
Oh , yes . It 's just for blood sugar and so forth .
Nothing to be concerned about . You 're pregnant . Don 't worry .
All right . Well , I 'll come in on Monday .
- All right . Now , don 't forget the pills . - No , I won 't .
- Good-bye , Mrs. Woodhouse . - Good-bye , Dr. Hill .
Blood sugar ?
What 's that ?
Oh ! That 's great ! That 's just great !
- Father . - Ah , Mother .
- [ Whistles ] - Guy ... Guy , listen .
Let 's , uh , make this a new beginning , okay ?
A new openness and talking to each other ...
because we haven 't been open .
It 's true . I 've been so goddamned self-centered .
That 's what the whole trouble is .
And you know I love you , don 't you , Ro ? I do .
- I swear to God I 'm gonna be as open ... - It 's my fault as much as yours .
No , bull ! It 's mine . Now , you bear with me ...
and I 'm gonna try and do better , you hear ?
Oh , Guy !
[ Chuckling ]
What ?
Fine way for parents to be carrying on .
Hey , you know what I 'd love to do ?
- What ? - Tell Minnie and Roman .
Oh , I know , I know . It 's , uh ...
it 's , uh , supposed to be a deep , dark secret ...
but I 've already told them that we were trying .
They were so pleased .
Tell them .
- Back in two minutes ? - Mm-hmm .
You 're pregnant .
Another blood sample .
- # Ta-da # - Now , that 's what I call good news !
Ah , honey , congratulations !
- Thank you . - Our best wishes , Rosemary .
- Thank you very much . - We are more pleased than we can say .
We didn 't have any champagne on hand , but this will do just as nicely .
- When are you due , dear ? - June 28 .
Oh , it 's gonna be so exciting . Listen , dear , you got a good doctor ?
Oh , yes , a very good one .
One of the top obstetricians is a dear friend of ours .
Abe Sapirstein . Delivers all the society babies .
Abe Sapirstein ? One of the finest obstetricians in the country .
Wasn 't he on Open End a couple of years ago ?
That 's right .
- Ro ? - Uh ...
- Well , what about Dr. Hill ? - Don 't worry about Hill .
I 'll tell him something . You know me .
Listen , I won 't let you go to no Dr. Hill nobody ever heard of .
The best is what you 're gonna have , young lady .
- Where 's your telephone , huh ? - It 's in the bedroom .
He 's a brilliant man . Very sensitive .
- Ro , sit down , sit down ! - No , I 'm fine .
Abe ? Minnie . Fine .
Listen , Abe , a dear friend of ours just found out today she 's pregnant .
Yeah , isn 't it ? I 'm in her apartment right now .
We told her you 'd be glad to take care of her .
You wouldn 't charge her none of your fancy society prices , neither .
Uh-huh . Just wait a minute . Rosemary , tomorrow morning at 11 : 00 ?
- All right . - Yeah , 11 : 00 's fine , Abe .
Uh-huh . Yeah , well , you too .
No . No , no , no . Not at all .
All right . Well , let 's hope so . Good-bye .
- Well , there you are . - Hey , thanks a million , Minnie .
Yes , I don 't know how to thank you , both of you .
Just have a fine , healthy baby , that 's all .
[ Gasps ] My , I can 't wait to tell Laura-Louise .
Oh , uh ...
please don 't tell anyone else , not right away .
No , she 's right . There 's plenty of time .
Now , to a fine , healthy baby .
- Hear , hear ! - Hear !
Andy ?
Or Susan ?
Susan !
[ Women Chattering ]
[ Minnie Laughing ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Mumbling ]
Please don 't read books .
No pregnancy was ever exactly like the ones described in the books .
And don 't listen to your friends either .
No two pregnancies are ever alike .
- Dr. Hill prescribed vitamin pills . - No pills .
Minnie Castevet has a herbarium .
I 'm gonna have her make a daily drink for you that 'll be fresher , safer ...
and more vitamin-rich than any pills on the market .
Any questions you have , call me night or day .
Call me , not your Aunt Fanny . That 's what I 'm here for .
- Here . - What 's in it ?
Snips and snails and puppy dogs ' tails .
That 's fine , but what if we want a girl ?
Do you ?
- It 'd be nice if the first one were a boy . - Well , there you are .
- No , really , what is in it ? - A raw egg , gelatin , herbs ...
Tannis root ?
Some of that , along with some other things .
Don 't be so violent , Harry .
If you want to be stupid , be nonviolent stupid .
I 'm in love with no one , especially not your fat wife .
I 'm a hopeless cripple ...
What 's that ?
I 've been to Vidal Sassoon .
Don 't tell me you paid for that .
Guy , I have a pain .
- Where ? - In here .
- Just now ? - Since Monday . A sharp pain .
- Did you see Sapirstein ? - I 'm seeing him on Wednesday .
This is ridiculous ! Why didn 't you see Sapirstein ?
- I mean , why didn 't you say anything ? - I see him Wednesday , regular .
An entirely natural expansion of the pelvis .
You can fight it with ordinary aspirin .
I was afraid it might be an ectopic pregnancy .
" Ectopic " ? I thought you weren 't gonna read books , Rosemary .
- It was staring at me in the drugstore . - And all it did was worry you .
Will you go home and throw it away , please ?
- I will . I promise . - The pains will be gone in two days .
Ectopic pregnancy !
I look awful .
What are you talking about ? You look great .
It 's that haircut that looks awful .
If you want the truth , honey , that 's the worst mistake you ever made .
My God !
It 's Vidal Sassoon . It 's very " in . "
What 's wrong with you ?
- Do I look that bad ? - Terrible !
You 're not on one of those Zen diets , are you ?
- No . - Then what is it ?
Have you seen a doctor ?
Hutch , I might as well tell you . I 'm pregnant .
Oh , rubbish !
Pregnant women gain weight , they don 't lose it .
I don 't sleep well .
I have stiff joints or something , so I get a pain .
Nothing serious .
Well , congratulations . You must be very happy .
Oh , I am . We both are .
- Who 's your obstetrician ? - Abraham Sapirstein .
Oh ! He delivered two of my daughter 's babies .
- He 's one of the best in the city . - When did you see him last ?
- Um , yesterday . - And ?
And he says it 's fairly common .
How much weight have you lost ?
About , uh , three pounds .
Oh , nonsense . You 've lost far more than that .
It 's perfectly normal to lose a little at first .
Later on I 'll be gaining .
Well ...
we must assume Dr. Sapirstein knows whereof he speaks .
He should . He charges enough .
We 're getting bargain rates . Our neighbors are close friends of his .
- [ Door Buzzer Sounds ] - I 'll go .
No , no . Stay where you are . Hurts less when I move around .
Oh , I was just talking about you .
Favorably , I hope . Do you need anything from outside ?
- No . Thank you for asking . - Is Guy home already ?
- No , he won 't be home till 6 : 00 . - Oh .
A friend of ours is here .
Would you ... Would you like to meet him ?
- Well , if I won 't be intruding . - No , no . Please come in .
Hutch , this is Roman Castevet .
- Edward Hutchins . - How do you do ?
- How are you , sir ? - I was just telling Hutch ...
it was you and Minnie who sent me to Dr. Sapirstein .
So Rosemary has told you the good news ?
- Yes , she has . - We must see she gets plenty of rest .
I was a bit alarmed by her appearance .
Well , she has lost some weight , but that 's quite normal for the early months .
Later on , she 'll gain ... probably far too much .
- So I gather . - Please sit down .
Mrs. Castevet makes a vitamin drink for me every day from fresh herbs she grows .
Yes , all according to Dr. Sapirstein 's directions , of course .
He 's inclined to be suspicious of commercially prepared vitamin pills .
Is he indeed ? Why , surely they 're manufactured ...
under every imaginable safeguard .
That 's quite true , but commercial pills ...
can sit for months on a druggist 's shelf ...
and lose a great deal of their original potency .
I hadn 't thought of that .
I like the idea of having everything fresh and natural .
I 'll bet expectant mothers chewed bits of tannis root ...
when nobody 'd even heard of vitamin pills .
- Tannis root ? - It 's one of the herbs she puts in the drink .
Or is it an herb ? Can a root be an herb ?
You sure you don 't mean anise or orris root ?
- No , tannis . - Hmm .
Look .
It 's good luck too .
[ Exclaims ]
It doesn 't look like root matter .
More like mold or fungus of some kind .
- Is it ever called by any other name ? - Not to my knowledge , no .
Hmm .
" Tannis " ... I must look it up in the encyclopedia .
What a pretty holder or charm or whatever it is .
The Castevets gave it to me .
You and your wife seem to be taking better care of Rosemary than her own parents .
We 're very fond of her , and of Guy too .
Now , if you 'll excuse me , I 'll have to go .
- My wife is waiting for me . - It 's a pleasure to have met you .
Don 't bother , Rosemary .
We 'll meet again , I 'm sure .
I 've just noticed he has pierced ears .
- # # [ Piano : " Für Elise " ] - Pierced ears and piercing eyes .
What 's she like ?
Nosy . Funny .
Guy 's gotten very close to them .
I suppose they 've become sort of parent figures for him .
And you ?
- I ... I don 't know . - [ Door Opens ]
Sometimes I think they 're too friendly and helpful .
Hey , what a surprise . How are you , Hutch ? Good to see you .
You 're the surprise . What happened ?
They stopped for a rewrite , those dumb bastards .
Uh , stay where you are . Nobody move .
- Would you like some coffee ? - Love some !
Loot .
It seems congratulations are in order .
- Yeah , it 's wonderful , isn 't it ? - When 's the baby due ?
June 28 .
Did you know that Dr. Sapirstein delivered two of Hutch 's grandchildren ?
- Really ? - Mm .
I met your neighbor ... Roman Castevet .
Oh , did you ? Funny old duck , isn 't he ?
Guy , did you ever notice he has pierced ears ?
- You 're kidding . - No , I 'm not . I saw .
It 's a shame we haven 't seen more of you lately , Hutch ...
but with me so busy and Ro the way she is , we really haven 't seen anyone .
- Perhaps we can have dinner together soon . - You 're not going , are you ?
- Thanks for the coffee , my dear . - Thank you for coming , my dear .
- This isn 't mine . It must be yours . - Right you are .
Have you thought about names , or is it too soon ?
Andrew or Douglas if it 's a boy . Melinda or Sarah if it 's a girl .
" Sarah " ? What happened to " Susan " ?
Say , is there another of these around ?
Oh .
- I don 't see it , Hutch . - No , it 's not here .
Hmm . Oh , probably left at the City Center .
I 'll stop back there . Let 's really have that dinner , shall we ?
- Definitely . - Next week .
- Good-bye . - Good-bye .
- Bye . - Bye .
It was a nice surprise .
Guess what he said .
- What ? - I look terrible .
Oh , good old Hutch . He 's spreading cheer wherever he goes .
I 'm gonna get a paper , honey .
- He 's a professional crepe-hanger . - He 's not a professional crepe-hanger .
Then he 's one of the top-ranking amateurs .
- [ People Chattering ] - [ Gunfire ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Guy ] Hello ? Oh , uh , no . She 's not feeling too well .
I think she 's asleep .
Oh , I wouldn 't ...
Well , she could be , yeah . She wasn 't feeling well .
All right . Can you hold on a minute ?
It 's Hutch . He wants to speak to you .
Oh .
I told him you were resting , but he said it couldn 't wait .
- Hutch ? - Tell me , dear , do you go out at all ?
Well , I-I haven 't been going out . Why ?
Can you meet me tomorrow morning at 11 : 00 in front of the Time-Life Building ?
If you want me to .
- What is it ? Can 't you tell me now ? - I 'd rather not .
We can have an early lunch , if you 'd like .
- That would be nice . - Good . 11 : 00 , then ?
Okay . Oh , did you find your glove ?
No , they didn 't have it . Good night , Rosemary .
- Sleep well . - You too . Good night .
- What was that ? - He wants to talk to me .
- What about ? - I don 't know . He wouldn 't say .
[ Scoffs ] I think those boys ' adventure stories are going to his head .
Where are you meeting him ?
Uh , Time and Life Building tomorrow at 11 : 00 .
[ Phone Clatters On Table ]
This is ridiculous .
You 're pregnant ... I 've got the yens . I 'm gonna get an ice-cream cone . Want one ?
- Yeah , I 'd love one . - Vanilla ?
- Uh , okay . - Okay .
[ Door Opens , Shuts ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
- Hi ! - Hi . Minnie , I 'm going out now ...
- so I won 't have my drink at 11 : 00 . - That 's fine , dear .
Take it later . Buzz me when you get back , huh ?
[ Santa Claus ] Merry Christmas . Merry Christmas .
Pain , begone . I will have no more of thee .
[ Helicopter Passing Overhead ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Line Ringing ]
- [ Woman ] Yes ? - Is this Edward Hutchins 's apartment ?
- Yes . Who is this , please ? - My name is Rosemary Woodhouse .
I had an appointment with Mr. Hutchins . Is he there ?
- Hello ? - He was taken ill this morning .
- " Taken ill " ? - Yes .
He 's in a deep coma at St. Vincent 's Hospital .
That 's awful .
I just spoke to him last night about 10 : 30 .
I spoke to him at 11 : 00 .
- Who is this ? - You don 't know me , Rosemary .
I 'm Grace Cardiff , Hutch 's friend .
And do they ... do they know what 's causing it ?
No , they don 't know yet . At the moment , he 's totally unresponsive .
- Oh , my God . - I 'm going to the hospital now .
- Is there anything I can do ? - Not really .
All right . Um , thank you .
Now , this is what I call the long arm of coincidence !
[ Chuckling ] Oh , God !
I said to myself , " As long as Rosemary 's goin ' out ...
I might as well go out and do a little bit of Christmas shoppin ' . "
And now here you are and here I am . Isn 't that somethin ' ?
Aw , darlin ' , what 's the matter ? You feel all right ?
Aw . Aw , you poor thing .
You know what I think ? I think we better be goin ' home now .
- What do ya say ? - No , no . You have your shopping to do .
Aw , shoot . There 's two more weeks . [ Blowing Whistle ]
It 'll stop any day now .
It 's like a wire inside me getting tighter and tighter .
Usually , older women ...
with less flexible joints have this sort of trouble .
- I 'm not going out anymore . - You don 't have to .
- One minute to go ! - [ Champagne Cork Pops ]
Rosemary , I want you to meet Dr. Shand .
He used to be a famous dentist . He made the chain for your charm .
Oh . How do you do ?
Yeah . Come on , sweetie . Put this hat on your head .
Doctor , it looks great . Come over here .
- Minnie , Minnie ! - Thank you .
- Happy New Year . - Happy New Year .
- [ Indistinct ] - Happy New Year .
- [ Clock Chiming ] - To 1966 !
- The Year One ! - [ Noisemakers Blowing ]
[ Water Running ]
What the hell are you doing ?
Planning the menu .
We 're having a party a week from Saturday .
It 's for our old fr ... I mean , our young friends .
Minnie and Roman are not invited .
Neither is Laura-Louise . Nor is Dr. Sapirstein .
It 's gonna be a very special party . You have to be under 60 to get in .
Well !
For a minute there , I didn 't think I was going to make it .
Oh , you 'll make it , all right . You can be a bartender .
Oh , swell .
Do you really think it 's such a good idea ?
I think it 's the best idea I 've had in months .
Don 't you think you ought to check with Dr. Sapirstein first ?
What for ? I 'm just giving a party . I 'm not gonna swim the English Channel .
What about the pain ?
Oh , haven 't you heard ? It 'll go away in a day or two .
[ Minnie ] That looks interesting . What 's it for ?
We 're having some people over on Saturday .
- Oh , you feel up to entertaining ? - Yes , I do .
These are old friends I haven 't seen in a long time .
They don 't even know yet that I 'm pregnant .
I 'll give you a hand if you like . I can help you dish things out .
No . Thank you , Minnie , but I can manage .
It 's gonna be a buffet , and we 're getting a bartender , so ...
Oh . I 'll help you take the coats .
Oh , no , really . You do too much for me as it is .
Well , let me know if you change your mind .
- Drink your drink , hon . - # # [ Piano : " Für Elise " ]
I 'd rather not .
Not right this minute . I 'll drink it in a little while .
- Well , it don 't do to let it stand . - No , I won 't wait too long .
You go on back , and I 'll bring the glass back to you later .
- Oh , I 'll wait . I 'll save you the walk . - You 'll do no such thing .
It makes me very nervous when people watch me cook . Now scoot .
Don 't let it stand too long . It 's gonna lose its vitamins .
- # # [ Pop Rock ] - You dirty , stinkin ' secret-keeper !
- Congratulations ! - Congratulations !
- Thank you . - [ Woman ] Hey , Rosie ?
- Yeah ? - Bob and Lee got stuck ...
at another party , dear , but they 'll be over right away .
- Oh , fine . - [ Door Buzzer Sounds ] - Rosie , you 're so lucky .
- It 's a fantastic house ! - I know .
You look like a piece of chalk !
You make him feed you , love .
- Adrian Marcato lived here . - Yeah , and the Trench sisters too .
- Trent sisters ? - Trench . They ate little children .
He doesn 't just mean they ate them .
He means they ate them .
I make the first ones strong to get them happy .
- Then I go light and conserve , eh ? - [ Woman ] Rosie , do you feel okay ?
You look a little tired .
Yeah , well , thanks for the understatement .
How do you like C.C. Hill ? Isn 't he a dream boy ?
Mm-hmm .
- But I ... I 'm not going to him . - You 're not ?
I 've got another doctor named Sapirstein , an older man .
- Oh , congratulations , Papa . - Thanks . Weren 't nothing to it .
Ro , I 'm gonna take that dip inside , all right ?
Oh , yeah , please . See my flowers ?
Yeah . Elise , would you give me a hand with the ...
Oh , yeah . Sure .
Hey , whatever happened to the other guy ? Is he still blind ?
Donald Baumgart ? You know who he is .
- He 's the boy that Zöe Piper lives with . - Oh , is he the one ?
- Yeah , he 's writing a play . - Is he still blind ?
- Yeah . - Excuse me .
And he 's going through hell trying to make the adjustment .
- He dictates and Zöe writes . - Congratulations !
- [ Mouthing Words ] - Can you imagine the courage of this guy ?
He 's just blind a few months , you know .
Are you all right ?
Yeah , I 'm fine . I just had a cramp for a minute .
It 's all right . It 's good for her . Let her cry it out .
It 's all right , darling . It 's all right . Sit down . Sit down .
Sit down .
- Hey , let me in , will ya ? - Sorry . Girls only .
- I want to talk to Rosemary . - You can 't . She 's busy .
- I have to wash these ... - Use the bathroom .
It hurts so much . I 'm so afraid the baby 's gonna die .
When did the pain start ?
In , uh , November .
- November ? - What ?
You have been in pain since November ...
and he 's not doing anything to help you ?
He says it 's gonna stop .
- Why don 't you go to see another doctor ? - No , he 's very good .
He was on Open End .
Well , he sounds like a sadistic nut .
Rosemary , pain like that is a warning ...
that something isn 't right .
Go see Dr. Hill .
- Go see anybody besides that ... that ... - That nut !
- You can 't go on suffering like this . - I won 't have an abortion .
Nobody 's telling you to have an abortion .
Just go to see another doctor , that 's all .
The thing to do now is move .
- Guy ? - Yeah ?
I 'm going to Dr. Hill Monday morning .
Dr. Sapirstein is either lying , or he 's ...
I don 't know ... out of his mind .
Pain like this is a warning something 's wrong .
- Rosemary ... - And I 'm not drinking Minnie 's drink anymore .
I want vitamins in pills like everyone else .
I haven 't drunk it for the last three days . I 've thrown it away .
- You 've what ? - I 've made my own drink .
Is that what those bitches were giving you in there ?
Is-Is that their hint for today ?
They 're my friends . Don 't call them bitches .
They 're a bunch of not-very-bright bitches ...
who ought to mind their own goddamn business !
All they said was , get a second opinion .
Rosemary , you got the best doctor in New York .
Do you know who Dr. Hill is ? He 's a Charley Nobody . That 's who he is !
I 'm tired of hearing how great Dr. Sapirstein is .
Well , we 'll have to pay Sapirstein , we 'll have to pay Hill ...
It 's out of the question . Uh-uh . Uh-uh .
No , I 'm not changing . I just want to go to Dr. Hill and get a second opinion .
I won 't let you do it , Ro .
I mean , because it 's , uh ...
it 's not fair to Sapirstein .
" Not fair to " ...
What are you talking about ? What about what 's fair to me ?
Look , if you want a second opinion ...
You tell Sapirstein ...
and-and-and let him decide who gives it .
No ! I want Dr. Hill ! If you won 't pay , I 'll ...
At least have that much courtesy to the top man in the field .
Ro ?
Rosemary ? What is it ?
[ Whispering ] It stopped .
What ?
The pain stopped . Just like that .
- " Stopped " ? - Stopped .
What was in that drink you made ?
Um , eggs ...
milk , sug ... sugar .
What else ?
Rosemary , for chrissakes , what else was in that drink ?
It 's alive !
Guy , it 's moving .
It 's alive . It 's all right .
- Feel . Feel . - Oh , yeah . I felt it .
- Don 't be scared . It won 't bite you . - Oh , it 's wonderful . It 's really ...
I feel it kicking .
It 's alive ! It 's moving !
I 'll , uh , clean up some of this mess .
Watch the walls , now , fellas .
Sort of in the center there .
- Thanks , boys . Have one on the baby . - Thank you very much .
- What 's that for ? - It 's my hospital suitcase .
Honey , you got three weeks .
[ Phone Ringing ]
Yes ?
Hello , Mrs. Cardiff .
No .
Oh , my God .
Oh , my God !
Yes , of course I will .
[ Hangs Up Phone ]
Hutch is dead .
I feel awful . All this time , I didn 't even think of him .
[ Bells Tolling ]
Doctor , good-bye . Doris , we 'll see you later .
- Good-bye . - I beg your pardon .
I 'm Mrs. Woodhouse . I knew your father .
- Oh , so you 're Rosemary . - I 'm terribly sorry .
Thank you . This is my sister , Edna .
- How do you do ? - And my husband .
- [ Both ] How do you do ? - I 'm sorry to be late .
- Excuse me . - Yes ?
- I 'm Grace Cardiff . - Oh , I was hoping to meet you .
Thank you for calling me .
I was going to mail this , but then I thought you would be here .
- What is it ? - A book .
Hutch regained consciousness at the end ...
and he thought it was the next morning .
- You know , when you had the appointment ? - Oh , yes .
I wasn 't there , but he told the doctor to make sure ...
- that you got the book on his desk . - Thank you .
Oh , and I 'm to tell you : The name is an anagram .
- The name of the book ? - Apparently .
He was delirious , so it 's hard to be sure .
# # [ Piano : " Für Elise " ]
[ Door Buzzer Sounds ]
I heard you come in . It certainly wasn 't very long .
- I was late . I couldn 't get a taxi . - Ah , what a shame .
Oh , you got mail already ?
Somebody gave it to me .
Here . I 'll hold it .
Book ?
Oh , I know that house . The Gilmores used to live there .
- Oh ? - Yeah .
Oh , I 've been there lots of times .
" Grace " ... that 's one of my favorite names .
- It is ? - Yeah . You need anything ?
- Nothing , thank you . - Take a nap , why don 't you ?
- I 'm going to . - Yeah . Good-bye .
" Born in Glasgow in 1846 ...
he was soon after brought to New York .
He resided for several years in the United St ...
He was attacked by a mob outside the Bram ... "
Outside . Not in the lobby .
There are no witches . Not really .
" The name is an anagram . "
Now , that really makes sense .
Poor Hutch .
[ Guy ] Ro ?
What 's with the chain ?
What 's the matter ?
- Are you all right ? - I 'm fine .
- Oh . - Oh , thank you .
- How was the funeral ? - Okay .
I got the shirt that was in The New Yorker .
I got that shirt that was in The New Yorker .
That 's nice . Do you know who Roman really is ?
- What do you mean , honey ? - He 's Adrian Marcato 's son .
- What ? - Come here .
I 'm gonna show you something .
" Roman Castevet " is " Steven Marcato " rearranged .
It 's from Hutch .
Look .
And look here . There he is when he was 13 .
See the eyes ?
- A coincidence . - In the same house ?
And look . Look here .
" Soon after that , in August 1886 ...
his son Steven was born . "
1886 . Got it ? That makes him 79 now .
No coincidence .
No , I guess not .
He 's Steven Marcato , all right .
Poor old geezer . With a crazy father like that ...
no wonder he switched his name around .
You ... You don 't think he 's the same ?
What do you mean ? A witch ?
Ro , are you kidding ? Oh , Ro , honey .
His father was a martyr to it .
- Do you know how he died ? - Honey , it 's 1966 .
This was published in 1933 .
There were covens in Europe - that 's what they 're called -
the , uh - the congregation -
covens in Europe , in America , and in Australia , and they have one right here .
That whole bunch ... the parties with the singing and the flute and the chanting ...
- those are esbats or sabbaths or whatever they 're called . - Honey , don 't get excited .
Read what they do , Guy ! They use blood in their rituals ...
and the blood that has the most power is baby 's blood .
And they don 't just use the blood . They use the flesh too .
Rosemary , for God sakes !
They 're not setting foot in this apartment ever again .
And they 're not coming within 50 feet of the baby .
They 're old people . They have a bunch of old friends .
Dr. Shand happens to play the recorder .
I 'm not taking any chances with the baby 's safety .
- We 're gonna sublet and move out . - We are not .
- Oh , yes , we are . - We 'll talk about it later .
And I don 't think you ought to read any more of that .
- Just this last chapter . - Not today , honey .
Look , your hands are shaking . Now , come on . Give it to me .
- You 'll read it tomorrow . - Guy ...
I mean it , now . Give it to me .
Fantastic . Absolutely fantastic .
- What 'd you say the name was ? Machado ? - [ Rosemary ] Marcato .
Fantastic . I think he told me once his father was a coffee importer .
He told Guy he was a producer .
I understand how disturbed you must be to have him for a close neighbor .
I don 't want anything more to do with him . Or Minnie .
I can 't take the slightest chance where the baby 's safety is concerned .
Absolutely .
Any mother would feel the same way .
Is there any chance at all that maybe ...
Minnie put something harmful in those drinks or those little cakes ?
No , Rosemary . I 'd have seen evidence of it long ago .
- I won 't take anything else from her . - You won 't have to .
I can give you some pills that 'll be adequate these last few weeks .
In a way , this may be ...
the answer to Minnie and Roman 's problem too .
- What do you mean ? - Roman 's very ill .
In fact , confidentially ...
he has no more than a month or two left .
- I had no idea . - He wanted to pay a last visit to a few of his favorite cities .
They didn 't want to offend you by leaving before the baby 's birth .
I 'm sorry to hear that Roman isn 't well .
He 'd be extremely embarrassed if he knew what you found out .
Suppose we do this : I 'll tell them to leave on Sunday .
I 'll say I spoke to you , and you understand .
- Are you sure they 'll leave on Sunday ? - I 'll see to it .
[ Whistle Blowing ]
[ Minnie ] No matter where we are ...
our thoughts are gonna be with you every minute , darlin ' ...
till you 're all happy and thin again ...
and your sweet little boy or girl 's layin ' safe in your arms .
Thank you . Thank you for everything .
Yeah , you make Guy send us lots of pictures , hear ?
Yes , I will .
I 'm not going to wish you good luck , because you won 't need it .
You 're going to have a happy , happy life .
Have a good trip , and come back safely .
Mm , perhaps . But I may stay on ...
in Dubrovnik or Pescara or maybe Majorca .
We shall see . We shall see .
- Come back . - Bye , Minnie .
- Yeah , good-bye . - Good-bye , Roman .
- Bye . Good-bye . - Take care , now .
- Kennedy Airport , Pan Am Building , please . - [ All Shouting Good-byes ]
Oh , boy .
- [ Rosemary ] Guy ? - Hmm ?
Where 's my book ?
Oh , I , uh , put it in the garbage .
- What ? - I didn 't want you upsetting yourself anymore .
Guy , Hutch gave me that book . He left it to me .
- I wasn 't thinking about that . - That 's a terrible thing to do .
I 'm sorry . I wasn 't thinking about Hutch .
- [ Man ] Hey , watch out , lady ! - [ Tires Screech ]
[ Horns Honking ]
" In some cults it was believed ...
that a personal possession of the victim was necessary ...
and spells could not be cast ...
without one of the victim 's belongings . "
- [ Man ] Yeah ? - Is this Donald Baumgart ?
- That 's right . - This is Rosemary Woodhouse .
- Oh . - Guy Woodhouse 's wife ?
- Oh , yes . - I wanted to know ...
My God , you must be a happy little lady these days , huh ?
Living in the Bram . Rows of uniformed lackeys .
I wanted to know how you are , if there 's been any improvement .
Well , bless your heart . [ Chuckling ]
Guy Woodhouse 's wife , huh ? Well , I 'm splendid .
I 've only broke six glasses today .
Guy and I are both very unhappy ...
that he got his break because of your misfortune .
Well , what the hell , huh ?
That 's the way it goes , right ?
I 'm sorry I didn 't come along that day he came to visit you .
Vi ... Visit ? No .
Oh , you mean the day we met for drinks , huh ?
- Yes , that 's what I meant . - Right , right .
By the way , he has something of yours , you know .
What do you mean ?
- Don 't you ... Don 't you know ? - No .
Didn 't you miss anything that day ?
You ... You don 't mean my tie , do you ?
- Yes . - Oh . Well ...
Well , he 's got mine , and I 've got his .
- He can have it back . - I 'm sor ...
It doesn 't matter to me now what , uh ... [ Chuckles ] color tie I 'm wearing .
I didn 't understand . I thought he 'd only borrowed it .
No , no , no , no . It was ... It was a trade .
Or do you think he stole it ?
I have to hang up now .
I just wanted to know if there 'd been any improvement .
No . No , there isn 't .
It was nice of you to call . Bye .
[ Woman ] You aren 't in labor , are you ?
No , but I have to see the doctor . It 's very important .
Well , he has to leave at 5 : 00 , and there is Mrs. Byron .
- I 'm sure he 'll see you . Just sit down . - Thank you .
[ Woman ] How is it out there ?
- Oh , awful . Ninety-four . - Uh !
- [ Dr. Sapirstein ] See you next week . Make an appointment . - [ Woman ] Yes , I will .
- You 're due any day now , aren 't you ? - Tuesday .
- You 're smart to get it over with before August . - Yeah .
Mrs. Byron . He 'll see you right after .
- Thank you . - Let 's see .
- July the 10th ? - Um , what time ?
- 4 : 00 ? - Fine . - All righty .
- See you then . - Thank you .
- Bye-bye . - Bye . Good luck .
Thank you .
[ Door Opens , Shuts ]
Mmm . That smells nice . What is it ?
Oh , my ... It 's called Detchema .
Mm . Well , it 's a big improvement ...
on your regular , if you don 't mind my saying .
That wasn 't a perfume . That was a good-luck charm . I threw it away .
Good . Maybe the doctor will follow your example .
- Dr. Sapirstein ? - He has the aftershave .
But it isn 't , is it ? [ Chuckles ] I don 't think he has a good-luck charm .
Anyway , he has the same smell once in a while , whatever it is ...
and when he does ... oh , boy !
Haven 't you ever noticed ?
No .
Maybe you thought it was your own you were smelling .
What is it , a chemical thing ?
Will you excuse me a moment , please ?
My husband is waiting outside . I have to go and tell him something .
I 'll be back in a minute .
[ Muttering ]
[ Line Ringing ]
- [ Woman ] Dr. Hill 's office . - Dr. Hill , please .
This is his answering service . Would you like to leave a message ?
Ye ... Uh , yes .
My name is Rosemary Woodhouse . Woodhouse .
And , um , would you ask him to call me back right away , please ?
Uh , my number is ...
475-2598 .
It 's an emergency . I 'm in a phone booth .
All right .
Quickly please , Dr. Hill . Call me .
Oh ... Oh , really ? Did ... did he really say that ?
Oh , he didn 't say that !
What else was it that he said ?
Oh , that ... that 's wonderful .
That 's won ... That 's mar ... marvelous .
- [ Ringing ] - Yes , Dr. Hill ?
[ Woman ] Did I get the name right ? Is it Rosemary Woodhouse ?
- Yes . - Are you Dr. Hill 's patient ?
No . Uh , yes .
I mean , well , I 've seen him once .
Um , please , please tell him he has to speak to me .
It 's important . Tell him to call me , hmm ?
- All right . - Thank you .
All of them . All of them .
All in it together .
All of them ... All of Them Witches .
Don 't you worry , little Andy or Jenny .
I 'll kill them before I let them touch you .
- [ Ringing ] - Yes ? Doctor ...
- Mrs. Woodhouse ? - Yes .
Oh , thank you , thank you for calling me .
- I thought you were in California . - No .
No , I 've been to another doctor ...
and he isn 't good , Dr. Hill .
He 's been lying to me and giving me ...
unusual kinds of drinks and capsules .
The baby 's due on Tuesday . Remember you told me June 28 ?
- Well , I want you to deliver it . - Mrs. Woodhouse ...
No , please , let me ... let me talk to you .
Let me come and explain what 's been going on .
I can 't stay too long here .
They 'll be coming looking for me .
Dr. Hill ? Dr. Hill , there 's a plot .
I know that sounds crazy . You 're probably thinking ...
" My God , this poor girl has really flipped . "
But I haven 't flipped , Dr. Hill .
I swear by all the saints I haven 't .
There are plots against people , aren 't there ?
Yes , I suppose there are .
Well , there 's one against me and my baby .
Come to my office tomorrow after 5 : 00 , and we 'll ...
Now . Right now .
Mrs. Woodhouse , I 'm not at my office now . I 'm home .
- I 've been up since yesterday morning ... - I beg you !
I beg you .
I can 't stay here .
- My office at 8 : 00 . - Yes . Thank you .
- All right . - Oh , wait . Dr. Hill ?
- Yes ? - My husband may call you and ask if ...
I 'm not gonna speak to anyone . I 'm gonna take a nap .
Thank you .
Keep the change .
Driver , please , could you wait and watch ...
until I 'm inside the door ?
He lied to you . He said we were going to Hollywood .
The worst thing of all ... he 's involved with them as well .
He sleeps in pajamas now . He never used to before .
He 's probably hiding a mark .
You know , they give you marks when you join .
All sorts of rituals . They hold sabbaths there .
You could hear them singing through the wall .
Guy - my husband , Guy - said it was Dr. Shand ...
one of these people , playing a recorder .
Now , how did he know it was Dr. Shand unless he was there with them ?
Uh , they 're very clever people .
They planned everything right from the beginning .
They probably made some sort of deal with Guy .
They gave him success , and he promised them ...
our baby to use in their rituals .
I know this sounds crazy , but I 've ... I 've got books here .
Look .
There was another actor like him , Donald Baumgart ...
and they put a spell on him .
They cast a spell on him and made him blind ...
so that Guy could get his part .
Look . Here .
I had this friend , Edward Hutchins . Maybe you heard of him .
A writer . He wrote stories for boys .
Anyway , he was my good friend since I first came to New York .
- May I keep this ? - Yes , please .
And , uh , anyway ...
once Mr. Hutchins came to visit me .
Came to visit me . It was the time I was having this pain , Doctor .
I was suffering so ... You can 't imagine how much I was suffering .
And they wouldn 't help me . Nobody would .
They were giving me a drink with tannis root in it ...
also witches ' stuff , tannis root .
Hutch came , and he immediately saw something was wrong .
He knew about witches , you see ?
Suddenly , Guy rushed in with his makeup still on , which he never did .
They probably called him to come home ...
and steal one of Hutch 's belongings , which he did .
Took his glove . And they put a spell on him too .
Put him in a coma . Three months later , he died .
Now , maybe all this is coincidence , but one thing is for sure :
They have a coven , and they want my baby .
It certainly seems that way .
I was afraid you wouldn 't believe me .
I don 't believe in witchcraft ...
but there 're plenty of maniacs and crazy people in this city .
The doctor 's name is Shand , you say ?
No , Dr. Shand is one of these people .
The doctor 's name is Sapirstein .
Abraham Sapirstein ?
Yeah .
- Do you know him ? - I 've met him once or twice .
To look at him , you 'd never think he ...
No , you wouldn 't . Not in a million years .
Would you like to go into Mount Sinai right now ?
This evening ?
Yeah , I would love to . Would that be possible ?
It 's difficult . We 'll try .
I want you to lie down and get some rest .
Thanks .
Anything they 've got . Even a broom closet would be fine .
I hope we can do better than that .
I 'll see what I can do , and then I 'll check you over .
Should I undress now ?
No , it 'll take me about a half an hour on the telephone .
You just lie down . Rest .
- Okay ? - Okay .
God bless Dr. Hill .
Everything 's gonna be okay now , Andy or Jenny .
We 're gonna be in a nice , clean hospital ...
with no visitors .
Oh .
Monsters .
Unspeakable !
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Door Opens ]
I was sleeping .
Come with us quietly , Rosemary .
Don 't argue or make a scene ...
because if you say anything more about witches or witchcraft ...
we 're gonna be forced to take you to a mental hospital .
You don 't want that , do you ? So put your shoes on .
We just want to take you home . No one 's gonna hurt you .
Or the baby . Put your shoes on .
She 's fine now .
- We 're going to go home and rest . - That 's all it takes .
- Thank you for your trouble , Doctor . - I 'm glad I could be of help , sir .
It 's a shame you had to come in here .
Good evening , Mrs. Woodhouse .
Mrs. Woodhouse !
[ Gasping ]
[ Gasping Continues ]
- Ro ! Ro ! - [ Pounding On Door ]
Ro ! Oh , Ro , baby .
Ro ! Ro !
- Come on . Open up , Ro . - Go to hell !
- Come on , honey . No one 's gonna hurt you . - You promised them the baby ! Get out !
I didn 't promise them anything . What are you talking about ? Promised who ?
- [ Dr. Sapirstein ] Rosemary ... - You too ! Get away !
[ Line Ringing ]
- [ Woman ] Hello ? - Elise ?
- Mrs. Dunstan is out . - Who 's this ?
- The babysitter . - Do you know where she went ?
- They went to the movies . - This is Rosemary .
Please ask her to call Rosemary the second she gets home .
It 's terribly urgent .
- Don 't forget , hmm ? - Don 't worry . I 'll tell her .
Thank you .
[ Floorboards Creaking ]
We don 't want to hurt you , Ro . Uh ...
We 're your friends , Rosemary .
There 's nothing to be afraid of , Rosemary . Honest and truly there isn 't .
This is nothing but a mild sedative to calm you down .
You know I wouldn 't let anyone ...
- Ro ! Ro ! - [ Screaming ]
- Ro ! Ro ! - Help me !
- Oh , Ro , baby . Stop . - Somebody help me !
Ro !
[ Muffled Shouts ]
Wait a minute ! Wait a minute , now .
- We happen to be in labor here . - [ Woman ] Here ?
- Here . - You 're gonna be all right , baby .
- You 're gonna be perfectly all right . I swear to God . - [ Phone Ringing ]
- It was supposed to be Doctors Hospital ! - Don 't go on like this , Ro , please .
- Doctors Hospital , with nurses ... - It 'll be perfectly all right .
- and everything clean and sterile ! - I give you my word of honor !
Hello ? No , she isn 't here , Elise . I 'll have her call you back .
[ Hangs Up Phone ]
Oh , Andy ... Andy or Jenny ...
I 'm sorry , my little darling .
Forgive me !
Hi .
Is it all right ?
Yes .
It 's fine .
What is it ?
A boy . [ Chuckles ]
Really ? A boy ?
And it 's all right ?
Yes .
- Where is it ? - [ Exclaims ]
Oh , my goodness !
Oh , dear , what a start you gave me ! My goodness !
The baby ... where is it ?
Oh , uh , you-you wait here one minute .
Where 's my baby ?
I 'll go find Dr. Abe . Ju ... Just wait .
Where 's the baby ?
Where is it ?
Honey ...
There were complications , Rosemary , but nothing that will affect future births .
It 's ...
Dead . It was in the wrong position .
In a hospital , I might 've been able to do something , but you wouldn 't listen .
[ Guy ] Honey , we can have others as soon as you 're better . I promise .
[ Dr. Sapirstein ] Absolutely . You can start on another in a very few months .
- [ Guy ] As soon as you 're better . - You lie .
I don 't believe you . You 're both lying .
- Honey . Honey ... - You 're lying ! It didn 't die !
You took it ! You 're lying !
You witches , you 're lying !
You 're lying ! You 're lying !
You 're lying !
Abe says it 's called ... prepartum .
I don 't know . It 's some kind of a hysteria .
Boy , you were really - kapow ! ... out of your mind .
Uh ... Yeah , I know where you got the idea ...
that Minnie and Roman were witches ... [ Chuckling ]
but how come you thought Abe and I joined the party ?
Um ...
Let 's face it , darling . You had the ...
prepartum crazies .
And now you 're gonna rest , and you 're gonna get over them .
I know this is the worst thing that ever happened to you ...
but from now on , everything 's gonna be roses .
Paramount 's within an inch of where we want ' em ...
and suddenly Universal 's interested too .
And we 're gonna blow this town ,
and we 're gonna be in the beautiful hills of Beverly ...
with a pool and a spice garden ... the whole schmear .
And the kids too , Ro . Scout 's honor .
You heard what Abe said .
Well , I got to run now and get famous .
Let me see your shoulder .
- Let me see your shoulder . - Are you kidding ?
Your left shoulder .
All right . Anything you say .
I generally prefer doing this to music .
Left shoulder .
Right shoulder .
And that 's as far as I go without a blue light .
The high-pressure area that we see here ...
- has been causing this extreme heat and humidity ... - [ Baby Crying ]
and unfortunately will be staying with us city dwellers ...
through the rest of the week .
It will be hot and overcast Upstate New York as well ...
with the possibility of thunder showers tonight and tomorrow ...
- [ Crying Continues ] - with gradual clearing by tomorrow night .
All you people leaving the city this upcoming weekend should find it hot ...
- [ Clicks Off ] - [ Crying Continues ]
[ Clicks Off ]
[ Crying Continues ]
Do you hear a baby crying ?
Why , no , I don 't , dear .
Now , you come and get into your bed now .
It 's time for you to take your pill .
- Did you turn the air conditioner off ? - Mm-hmm .
You mustn 't do that , dear .
Why , people are actually dying , it 's so hot .
What do you do with the milk ?
Why , uh , throw it away .
Oh . Your pill , Rosemary .
Hello , girls . Whew !
Ninety-five out .
Some new people moved on in up on eight .
Do they have a baby ?
How 'd you know that ?
I heard it crying .
Oh , wait a minute .
- Oh ! No . Don 't do that . - Why not ?
Uh ... a little messy , that 's all .
[ Lock Clicking ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Creaking Continues ]
[ Door Shuts ]
[ Rosemary ] Easy , easy .
" You 've got her too high . "
[ Man ] Not if he 's still waiting for a plane , he isn 't !
- [ People Laughing ] - [ Man ] Shh . Quiet , please .
[ Minnie ] Ah , hell , now , Hayato , you 're just making fun of me .
You 're pullin ' my leg , like we say over here .
[ Indistinct Conversations ]
[ Woman Screams ]
Rosemary , go back to bed .
You know you 're not supposed to be up and around .
- Is the mother ? - Uh , Rosemary ...
- Shut up ! - Rosemary ...
Shut up . You 're in Dubrovnik . I don 't hear you .
What have you done to it ?
What have you done to its eyes ?
He has his father 's eyes .
What are you talking about ? Guy 's eyes are normal !
What have you done to him , you maniacs ?
Satan is his father , not Guy .
He came up from hell and begat a son of mortal woman .
- Hail , Satan ! - Hail , Satan !
Satan is his father , and his name is Adrian .
He shall overthrow the mighty and lay waste their temples .
He shall redeem the despised ...
and wreak vengeance ...
in the name of the burned and the tortured !
- Hail , Adrian ! - [ All ] Hail , Adrian !
- No ! No ! - Hail , Satan ! Hail , Satan !
- Hail , Satan ! - He chose you out of all the world .
Out of all the women in the whole world , he chose you .
He arranged things ' cause he wanted you to be the mother of his only livin ' son .
- His power is stronger than stronger . - Hail , Satan !
- His might shall last longer than longer . - Hail , Satan !
No !
It can 't be !
- No ! - Go look at his hands .
And his feet .
Oh , God !
- God is dead ! - [ Woman ] Hail , Satan !
Satan lives ! The year is One !
- Hail , Satan ! - The year is One and God is done ! - Oh , God !
- The year is One ! - [ Several People ] Hail , Adrian !
[ Shouting Continues ]
Why don 't you help us out , Rosemary ?
Be a real mother to Adrian . You don 't have to join if you don 't want to .
Just be a mother to your baby .
Minnie and Laura-Louise are too old .
- It 's not right . - [ Doorbell Rings ]
Think about it , Rosemary .
Oh , God !
Oh , shut up with your " Oh , Gods , " or we 'll kill ya , milk or no milk !
You shut up . Rosemary 's his mother ...
so you show some respect .
[ Roman ] Come , my friend . Come see him .
Come see the child .
- [ Man ] What would you like to drink ? - [ Man # 2 ] I should like a Coca-Cola .
They , uh , promised me you wouldn 't be hurt ...
and you haven 't been , really .
I mean , supposing you had the baby and you lost it ?
Wouldn 't that be the same ?
And we 're getting so much in return , Ro .
Oh , Guy , let me introduce you to Argyron Stavropoulos .
How proud you must be ! Is this the mother ?
- Why in the name ... - Here , drink this . You 'll feel a little better .
What 's in it ? Tannis root ?
Nothin 's in it . Just plain , ordinary Lipton 's tea . You drink it .
[ Adrian Crying ]
[ Crying Continues ]
Get away from here ! Roman !
You 're rocking him too fast .
Sit down ! Get her out of here . Put her where she belongs .
You 're rocking him too fast . That 's why he 's crying .
- Mind your own business ! - Let Rosemary rock him .
Go on . Sit down with the others . Let Rosemary rock him .
- Why , she 's liable to ... - Sit down with the others , Laura-Louise .
[ Crying Continues ]
Rock him .
You 're trying to get me to be his mother .
Aren 't you his mother ?
[ Crying Continues ]
[ Crying Stops ]
# # [ Rosemary Vocalizing ]
# # [ Ends ]